大家好
hello everyone
我很高兴我们终于有了第一个视频记录
I'm so happy we finally have the first ever vidcount
今天我想说说拍子的事
so today I would like to talk about the beat
安迪人的开发者是巴雷特
the Andy man developer is Barrett
这是关于视频如何变成Grace
it's about how vid becomes Grace
使用安迪人的思维方式
using the mindset of Andy men
我的名字是Anthony Fu
my name is Anthony fu
我是vite View和nuxt的成员。
and I'm according a member of vite view and nuxt
我也是创造性的E测试视图使用
I'm also creative e test view use
unosses slider and unplugging
我目前在nuxt工作
I'm currently working at nuxt
实验室的框架团队
labs in the framework team
如果你喜欢视觉上的东西，这些是他们的项目
and if you prefer visually these are their items
所以你可以在github上找到我，地址是antfu或twitter上的MTV
so you can find me on github at antfu or twitter at MTV
fu7
在我们深入讨论需求之前
so before we dive into on demand
让我们先看看到底什么是需求
let's first see what the heck the on demand is
这就是我的童年
so this was my childhood
在那个时代
back at that times
当我想看一部电影的时候
um that say when I want to watch a movie
我需要下载整个文件，以便播放它
I need to download the whole files in order to play it
这并不是真的要花39年的时间来下载
it's not really taking 39 years to download
但印度可能需要几个小时
but India it could take a few hours
这可能是一场恶梦
and it could be a nightmare
如果我想从十几部电影中挑出一部好的，那就是噩梦。
if I want to pick a good ones out of a dozen or movies
所以，现在要感谢点播流媒体服务
so nowadays thanks for the on demand streaming service
像YouTube或Netflix
like YouTube or Netflix
我们的生活变得更加容易
our lives becomes much easier
所以，如果我必须给 "不需要 "下一个定义的话
so if I have to give a definition to undemand
我想说的是，根据你的要求提供你需要的东西
I would say provide what you need upon the request
与传统的或一次性的方法相比
compared to the traditional or at once approach
我认为undemand有几个特点
I think undemand is offering a few prose
第一是高效，即你只
the first is efficient is that you only
加载你需要的部分
load the parts you need
第二是响应性和可定制性
and the second one is responsive and customizable
例如，如果你在两个不同的设备上观看同一部电影
for example if you are watching the same movies
在两个不同的设备上
on 2 different device
你手机上的那个会得到
the one on your phone will get
低分辨率的流
lower resolution streams
然后你的台式机，因为它有一个
then your desktop since it has a
较小的流
smaller stream
尖叫声很快就会出现
scream to come soon
这将使事情更加有效
that would make things more efficient
然后我们可以发现，网络本身
and then we could find that the web itself
实际上也是按需分配的
is actually also on demand
这使得一个美丽的东西也有了完全的意义
that makes the total sense for a beautiful to also
这样做
doing so
但事情并不完美
but things are not perfect
事实上，它也有一些问题
indeed it comes with some comes
首先是开销，如网络请求
the first is overhead like network request
水流等
waterflows etc
例如，在一个非常小的网络连接中
for example in a very pool network connection
在网上观看YouTube视频将是一种可怕的体验。
it will be a terrible experience to watch a
录像在线
YouTube videos online
正确的和分段的是营地能力
right and in segment is the campacity
它需要实际工作来实现和
it requires actual work to implement and
维护需求的功能
maintain the functionality of on demand
因为没有银弹
since there is no silver bullet
让我们看看它是如何做这些交易的
let's see how it made those trade off
我们正在讨论的是按需分配
we are talking about on demand
在几个不同的方面
in a few different aspects
第一个，也可能是最知名的一个
the first and probably the most well known one
适应是不需要处理的
is that fit is undemand on processing
它只提供你需要的模块
vite only transpire the modules you need
请求页面或所谓的捆绑
for the request pages or so called bundle
这
this
这允许饲料保持快速作为你的项目的女孩
this allows feed to keep fast as your project girls
第二种，我想把它称为按需分配。
and the second one I would like to call it on demand
策略
on strategies
我们实际上有不同的
we actually have different
在开发和生产中的需求
needs on development and production
在开发过程中，我们会不断地改变我们的代码
in development we are changing our code constantly
有一个良好的反馈回路是很重要的
and having a good feedback loop will be important
以看到这些变化
to see the changes
这将是开发人员的经验
and that will be developer experience
而在生产中
and in production
我们更关注错误的时间性能
we are more focusing on the wrong time performance
和包的大小
and the size of the bundle
这将是用户体验
and that will be user experience
因此，VT提供了两个不同的模具标签和buildto
so VT provide 2 different mold tab and buildto
为BOSS战提供最好的服务
provide the best to the boss war
因此，在开发过程中，VT提供了捆绑列表
so in development beat is offering bundle list
自动替换
automatic replacement
和死亡服务器
and the death server
以使这些事情按需发生
to make those things happens on demand
另一方面，在制作方面
on the other hands in productions
fit实际上是使用ro up来捆绑应用程序的
fit is actually using ro up to bundle the app
并提供优化，如Tracy game cosplating
and providing optimizations like Tracy game cosplating
和小型化
and minification
在此基础上
on top of that
尽管有两种不同的策略
even though there are 2 different strategies
我们仍然使其保持一致
we still make it consistent
通过提供一个共享配置和插件系统
by providing a share configurations and plugin system
通过进一步的努力
by taking it further
我们可以在自动化方面没有需求
we could have undemand on automatization
一个杂草可以提供不同的策略
a weed could provide different strategies
在不同的目标上
on different targets
我们实际上可以对不同类型的文件有更精细的策略
we could actually have more fine grain strategies on
不同类型的文件
different type of files
我们可以把
we could separate
我们可以把项目代码分成用户代码和注释模块
the project code into user code and the note modules
你从第三方安装的模块
you install from the 3rd party
所以我们的假设是
so we've made the assumptions is that
用户代码会经常改变
the user code will be changed frequently
而音符模块
while the note modules
只会在一段时间内改变一次
will be only changed once a while
假设
taking an assumption
将每个模块的用户代码作为捆绑列表提供给用户
vite serve user code per module as bundle list
同时将非模块捆绑成一个文件
while per bundling the non modules into a single file
弟弟可以更有效地消费
that brother could consume more efficiently
和
and
维特在代码中受伤，用于替换空心模块
vite injured in the code for hollow module replacement
或用户代码，而在非模块中跳过它
or user code while skipping it in not modules
最后是按需定制的好处
and finally the bonus of on demand the customizability
小白在开发中使用了一个DAB服务器
whit is using a dab servers in development
这意味着插件可以使用它来做一些
that means plugins could use it to do some
客户端服务器通信
client server communication
例如
for example
下面是小麦插件提供的页面
here are the pages provided by wheat plugging
检查
inspect
和检查她的小麦内部转换
and inspect her of wheat internal transformation
在这里我们可以看到
here we could see
一个视图文件正在被一些插件进行转换
a view file is being transformed by a few plugins
而你可以看到每一步的
and you can see the each step of the
插件被转换
plugging being transformed
而这里的视图
and here the view
单一的文件组件被转化为爵士乐手柄
single file component being transfiled into jazz grip
而重要的分析是将
and the important analyze changes the
浏览器兼容的导入语句。
the import statements into a browser compatible pass
而你正在看的幻灯片实际上是由
and the slides you are looking at is actually
由slided驱动，它是在fit之上的
powered by slided which is on top of fit
通过使用几种通信方式
by using a kind several communication
它允许你直接回到远处的系统中去
it allows you to directly right back to the far system
在一个页面里面
inside a page
例如，我可以打开slider的建筑编辑器
for example I can open up the building editor of slider
我可以说，把标题改成橙色
I can say that changed the title into orange
和湿的，你可以看到，这些变化被
and wet and you can see that the changes being
即时反映
reflect instantly
所以，既然Weed提供了很多需求的东西
so since weed providing a lot of things on demand
我想鼓励插件作者
I would like to encourage plugging authors to
在构建集成时也要考虑到不需求的问题
to also build integrations with undemand in mind
例如，在nuxt
for example in nuxt
我们正在为视图建立一个4堆栈烟花
we are building a 4 stack firework for view
而在白天，我们需要自杀式渲染
and in day we need suicide rendering
因为Noah jazz不能直接理解我们的
since Noah jazz cannot directly understand our
源代码，改变了我们的整个学校。
source code altering entire school of usfc
传统的方法是，我们把我们的应用程序捆绑在一起
the traditional approach is that we bundles our app
把我们的应用捆绑在一起，让Note js执行和渲染。
to plant jazz crit for note js to execute and render
但问题是
the problem is that
在开发时
in development time
服务器端的渲染
serverside renderings
我们的源代码是经常变化的
our source code are changes frequently
而这意味着我们必须审查
and that means we have to review the
整个捆绑式和提成式
entire bundles and the rais cudiates
在我们所做的每一个变化上
on every single changes we made
而且会有非常低的效率在
and there will be very inefficients in
导致效率非常低下，因为需求系统就像节拍一样
on demand systems that like beat
所以我们最好想出一个更好的办法来做到这一点
so we better figure out a better way to do that
在接下来的第三章中
in next 3
我们为Vid实现了按需渲染的表面I
we implement the on demand surface I rendering for vid
通过引入一个新的vid运行时间
by introducing a new vid runtime
称为VID Note
called vid note
而不是将整个广告捆绑在
instead of bundling the entire ad
而不是直接捆绑整个广告
vino directly
使用来自vid服务器的转换结果和
used the transform result from the vid server and
在需要时杀死它们
is killed them on demand
这也使得硬模块的替换成为可能
it also makes it possible for hard module replacement
仅仅通过拯救
by only rescue
改变的模块
the changed modules
这样做的结果是
this results not to have
在开发过程中提高10-15倍的性能
10 to 15 faster performance on development
取决于项目的规模
depending on the scale of the project
关于这个的技术细节
about the technical details of this
你可以参考我的博客文章，链接如下
you can refer to my blog post as the link below
最后，让我们简单介绍一下Win Notes。
and finally let's do a brief introduction to win notes
维诺是一种知识，因为
vino is a knowledge as
维生素管道的情人节力量
valentine's power by vite pipeline
它提供了上
it provides up
不需求的评估
undemand evaluations
而且它可以重复使用vite的配置
and it could reuse vite configurations
插件等，以便与你的客户应用保持一致
plugins etc to be consistent with your client app
与生俱来的小麦
inherent from wheat
它也有户外箱ESM和任务途径支持
it also has outdoor box esm and taskway support
它也有一个观察
it also has a watch
模式，可替代空洞的元帅
mode with hollow marshal replacement
与普通模式类似
similar to normal
和程序化的使用
and for programmatically usage
它有独立的几个客户端架构
it has separate several client architecture
所以你可以从其他线程中执行一个代码
so that you can execute a code from the other thread
甚至是另一个进程
or even another process
vino现在已经成为了下一个系列开发时间的动力
vino is now a powering next series development time
服务我渲染
service I rendering
并把它作为
and also make of it as
在适合的情况下测试烟花
the testing firework on fit possible
它也为历史提供了动力，是vite上的故事书替代品。
it also powers history the storybook alternative on vite
和view terminui
and view terminui
他们的终端UIS为视图
their terminal uis for view
演示vite如何使笔记成为可能
to demo about how vite make notes possible
我强烈建议你观看
I would highly recommend you to watch
丹尼尔即将发表的演讲
the upcoming talk by Daniel
和饲料
and for feeds
你肯定不想错过Vermeer的演讲
you definitely don't want to miss the talk by vermeer
一个测试中的求爱成员之一
one of the courting member of a test
今天就到这里吧
and that's it for today
最后我想
finally I would like
感谢所有支持我工作的赞助者
to thanks for all my subsponsors to supporting my work
如果你也喜欢我的作品
and if you enjoy my works as well
你可以考虑在kihab网站上提交我
you can consider submit me at kihab
以帮助我保持它们的可操作性
to help me keep them substantible
我的谈话内容可以在我的网站上找到。
the slice of my talk can be found on my website
和Tfu dummy
and tfu dummy
谢谢你，下次见
thank you and see you next time